Wyck Association Collection 1663-1972 Mss.Ms.Coll.52
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Writings, 1721-1970; 14.75 Linear feet 36 boxes
  - Caspar Wistar Haines II
    - Testimony: re. CWH II, 1935 (Box 112, Folder 298)
    - Book: in Spanish, n.c. (Box 112, Folder 299)
    - Report: re. business, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 300)
    - Essay: translated by CWH II (?), "medicinal properties of the fruit of the Capomo", n.d. (Box 112, Folder 301)
    - Essay: including re. Lehigh University, Mexico, engineering, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 302)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 303)
    - Notebook: re. engineering, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 304)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 305)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 306)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 307)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 308)
    - Notes: in Spanish, re. geometry, engineering, etc., n.d. (Box 113, Folder 309)
    - Notes: re. lecture by CWH II on St. Alban's church, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 310)
    - Notes: misc., including re. electricity at Wyck, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 311)
    - Poetry, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 312)
    - Prayers: collected and written by CWH II (Box 113, Folder 313)
    - Religious material: misc. including poems, scripture, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 314)
    - Reminiscence: re. Germantown, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 315)
    - Report: re. land in Mexico, collected by CWH II (Box 113, Folder 316)
    - Riddles, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 317)
  - Robert Bowne Haines II
    - Essays by RBH II "Watkins Glen" "A Visit to the Central Park...", 1871 (Box 113, Folder 318)
    - Journal Notes re. canoe trip, 1877 (Box 113, Folder 319)
    - Notes incl. re. canoes, 1877 (Box 113, Folder 320)
    - Speech re. Haines' micrometer gage by RBH I, 1892 (Box 113, Folder 321)
    - Journal "Alaska Tour", 1913 (Box 113, Folder 322)
    - Journal "West Indies Journal", 1913 (Box 113, Folder 323)
    - Essay "A Fortune in the Ash Dumps of Philadelphia", n.d. (Box 114, Folder 324)
  - Mary Morton Haines
    - Poem "`Owed' to Mary" by M.W.W.B., 1877 (Box 114, Folder 325)
    - Diary., n.d. (Box 114, Folder 326)
      Appears to be a series of essays in Japanese, possibly during M.M.H's three years at Friend's school in Tokyo.
    - Paraphrase re. 23rd Psalm; collected by MMH, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 327)
  - William Jones Haines
    - Notebook "Diary", 1881 (Box 114, Folder 328)
  - Jane Bowne Haines II
    - Account re. first land journey from Chihuahwa to U.S.A. copied by JBH II "Dedicated to Mr. Morris at the Highlands, 1840 (Box 114, Folder 329)
    - Diary, 1877-81 (Box 114, Folder 330)
    - "The Little Moonbeam" edited by JBH II, 1878 (Box 114, Folder 331)
    - Diary "Record of our Croquet Club", 1880 (Box 114, Folder 332)
    - Diary, 1881-1882 (Box 114, Folder 333)
    - Diary, 1885 (Box 114, Folder 334)
    - Notebook "Bryn Mawr College", 1887 (Box 114, Folder 335)
    - Diary, 1887 (Box 114, Folder 336)
    - Journal, 1892 (Box 114, Folder 337)
    - Notebook, 1892 (Box 115, Folder 338)
    - Notebook: List of books, 1894 (Box 115, Folder 339)
    - Notes re. history, JBH II's thesis, et al., 1898-1899 (Box 115, Folder 340)
    - Journal "3rd trip abroad with MWH", 1899 (Box 115, Folder 341)
    - Notebooks [Jane Bowne Haines I], 1802, 1804 (Box 115, Folder 342)
    - Note, 1902 (Box 115, Folder 343)
    - Notebook "Journal of a Driving Trip", 1903 (Box 115, Folder 344)
    - Journal "By Trolley in New England", 1904 (Box 115, Folder 345)
    - Notebook, 1905 (Box 115, Folder 346)
    - Journal: Trip to Mexico, 1908 (Box 116, Folder 347)
    - Notebook, 1914 (Box 116, Folder 348)
    - Calendar, 1914-15 (Box 116, Folder 349)
    - Notes, 1921 (Box 116, Folder 350)
    - Essay re. Timothy Matlack, 1928 (Box 116, Folder 351)
    - Notebooks, 1930-33 (Box 116, Folder 352)
    - Notes (Misc.) re. housecleaning, gardens, etc., c.1934-35 (Box 116, Folder 353)
    - Notebooks, 1934-1936 (Box 116, Folder 354)
    - Poem given to JBH from John Emlen, 1935 (Box 116, Folder 355)
    - Date Book, 1937 (Box 116, Folder 356)
    - Lists, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 357)
    - Poetry (Misc.), n.d. (Box 116, Folder 358)
    - Poetry, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 359)
    - Prose (Misc.), n.d. (Box 116, Folder 360)
  - Diedrich Jansen Haines
    - Notebooks: Lecture notes, 1893 (Box 117, Folder 361)
    - Notebooks, 1930 (Box 117, Folder 362)
    - Memoirs re. trip to Africa, 1930-31 (Box 117, Folder 363)
  - Robert Bowne Haines III
    - Journal re. travels in Europe and Near East, 1913 (Box 117, Folder 364)
    - Notebook "Plants and Diseases - Fruit", 1916-1917 (Box 117, Folder 365)
    - Notes: "New Jersey State Agriculture College", 1918 (Box 117, Folder 366)
    - Notebook, 1918 (Box 117, Folder 367)
    - Examination from American Institute of Agriculture, 1925 (Box 117, Folder 368)
    - Notes re. fruit trade and shipment, c.1930 (Box 117, Folder 369)
    - Notebook, 1931 (Box 117, Folder 370)
    - Notebook, 1937 (Box 117, Folder 371)
    - Speech of acceptance at the "Feast of Roses", 1941 (Box 117, Folder 372)
    - Sunday School Materials incl. notes, attendance record, 1944 (Box 117, Folder 373)
    - Notebook, c.1945 (Box 117, Folder 374)
    - Notebook, 1947 (Box 117, Folder 375)
    - Essays prepared for "Wyck Group" religious seminars, 1949-51 (Box 118, Folder 376)
    - Essays re. Wyck: By RBH III, also re. RBH III, 1950 (Box 118, Folder 377)
    - Notebook, 1950 (Box 118, Folder 378)
    - Notebook, 1951 (Box 118, Folder 379)
    - Prayer, 1951 (Box 118, Folder 380)
    - Notes (Travel) by C.L.Burkholder, 1954-56 (Box 118, Folder 381)
    - Notebook, 1957 (Box 118, Folder 382)
    - Testimony by G.R.H. Wood re. W. H. Griffith Thomas, 1960 (Box 118, Folder 383)
    - Essays by F. C. Glass: Prospecting in North Brazil, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 384)
    - Extract re. Wyck, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 385)
    - Lists of books, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 386)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 387)
    - Notes re. religion, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 388)
    - Notes (Misc.), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 389)
    - Scripture "Good News According to John" mimeographed, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 390)
  - Alphabetical List
    - Account re. Dennis Frith, 1809 (Box 118, Folder 391)
    - Account re. Isaac Jones Wistar, 1905 (Box 118, Folder 392)
    - Accounts re. Hartshorne family incl. journal, records, typescripts, 1715-1900 (Box 118, Folder 393)
    - Address by Marianna Brown, "Farewell address to little Charles", 1845 (Box 118, Folder 394)
    - Correspondence Course re. agriculture Lesson IV, 1898 (Box 118, Folder 395)
    - Essay by M. Boget "On Metallic watering, or the damasking of tin plates.", 1818 (Box 118, Folder 396)
    - Essay by Edmunds W. Claussen "Wedding Journey at Christmas", 1970 (Box 118, Folder 397)
    - Essay re. George Flagg - painter and nephew of Washington Allston, 1832 (Box 118, Folder 398)
    - Essay by Diedrich Jansen Haines II "Medico Legal aspects of Traumatic Surgery", n.d. (Box 118, Folder 399)
    - Essay by Ella Haines re country home, 1930 (Box 118, Folder 400)
    - Essay by Reuben Cope Haines "A Remarkable Artesian Well Water", 1894 (Box 118, Folder 401)
    - Essays: Misc. incl. method of preserving fish; education, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 402)
    - Essay "On the Coloring or Dyeing of Paper", n.d. (Box 118, Folder 403)
    - Essay "Pearlie's Story", n.d. (Box 118, Folder 404)
    - Essay "The Standard Apple Tree" (Box 118, Folder 405)
    - Essay by Isaac Jones Wistar re N. American Coal, 1892 (Box 118, Folder 406)
    - Extract fr. "letter of the Director of a large institution to his son.", n.d. (Box 118, Folder 407)
    - Extract by Mary Pusley from her journal, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 408)
    - Extract by Nicholas B. Wainwright re. James Pemberton and Isaac Greenleafe, 1952 (Box 118, Folder 409)
    - Extracts: Misc., n.d. (Box 118, Folder 410)
    - Journal re. farming, 1846 (Box 118, Folder 411)
    - Journal by Anthony Morris re. travels in Spain (typescript), 1816 (Box 118, Folder 412)
    - Manuscript by Edmunds W. Claussen "The Story of an Old House - WYCK", 1970 (Box 119, Folder 413)
    - Memoir by William Hartshorne re death of his daughter, Mary Lawrence Hartshorne, c.1821 (Box 119, Folder 414)
    - Memoirs: Counte de Miollis (in French), c.1820's (Box 119, Folder 415)
    - Miscellany re. James Carver incl. letters, notes, advertisements, and financial accounts, 1812-13 (Box 119, Folder 416)
    - Miscellany re. Henry Hudson (a runaway slave), c. 1819 (Box 119, Folder 417)
    - Miscellany re. T. Waldemeyer, journal translated by T. W., biography re. T.W., notes on Syria, c.1905 (Box 119, Folder 418)
    - Notebook by William H. Bowne re. mathematics, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 419)
    - Notebook by William H. Bowne; penmanship exercises, 1814 (Box 120, Folder 420)
    - Notebook "Catalogue of the books in the Juvenile Library" c.1820-30, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 421)
    - Notebook: Family history copied by Reuben Cope Haines, 1782 (Box 120, Folder 422)
    - Notebook: Historical data (copied), 1730-1918 (Box 120, Folder 423)
    - Notebook re. methematics, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 424)
    - Notebook "Method of Preserving Birds", 1820's (Box 120, Folder 425)
    - Notebook Poetry collected by "W.W.", n.d. (Box 120, Folder 426)
    - Notebook re. religion, c.1874 (Box 120, Folder 427)
    - Notebook: newspaper clippings collected by Joseph Wistar, Jr., 1844 (Box 120, Folder 428)
    - Notebooks: Poetry and letter collected by Mary Hart, 1923-25 (Box 120, Folder 429)
    - Notebooks: Poetry and letter collected by Mary Hart, 1923-25 (Box 120, Folder 430)
    - Notebooks: Miscllaneous, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 431)
    - Notebooks: Playscripts - "Euripedes Medea" and "Graeca Majora" (Box 120, Folder 432)
    - Notes re. cleaning rooms of yellow fever patients c. 1793, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 433)
    - Notes re. Family History, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 434)
    - Notes re. Phillip Freneau, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 435)
    - Notes re. "The Gold Coin of Nero", 1800 (Box 121, Folder 436)
    - Notes (Misc.), n.d. (Box 121, Folder 437)
    - Notes re Queen Anne chairs at Wyck, 1907 (Box 121, Folder 438)
    - Notes in Spanish, 1889 (Box 121, Folder 439)
    - Notes re. telescope, Christ Church, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 440)
    - Notes and Notebook by Caspar Wistar, M.D. re. religion, 1808-1832 (Box 121, Folder 441)
    - Obituaries re. Robert W. Bowne, and William H. Bowne (Box 121, Folder 442)
    - Penmanship Exercises, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 443)
    - Poetry, 1825 (Box 121, Folder 444)
    - Poetry by Esther Marshall Garrigues, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 445)
    - Poetry by Nathan G. Goodman re Wyck, 1925-30 (Box 121, Folder 446)
    - Poetry re. Margaret Haines "Margaret", 1804 (Box 121, Folder 447)
    - Poetry collected by Sarah Minturn, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 448)
    - Poetry: Misc., c. 1817 (Box 121, Folder 449)
    - Poetry: Misc., n.d. (Box 121, Folder 450)
    - Poetry: Misc., n.d. (Box 121, Folder 451)
    - Poetry: Misc., n.d. (Box 121, Folder 452)
    - Poetry collected by Elizabeth Morris "An Enigma" by Lord Byron, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 453)
    - Poetry by Pastorius, Daniel Francis, 1715 (Box 121, Folder 454)
    - Poetry by Caspar Wistar, M.D., 1837 (Box 121, Folder 455)
    - Poetry by Caspar Wistar "Yearly Meeting", n.d. (Box 121, Folder 456)
    - Poetry by Lydia Jones Wistar to her son, Isaac Jones Wistar, 1870 (Box 121, Folder 457)
    - Poetry by Owen Wister "Beethoven", 1882 (Box 121, Folder 458)
    - Poetry by Thomas Wistar, M.D., 1837 (Box 121, Folder 459)
    - Poetry by Thomas Wistar, M. D., 1837 (Box 121, Folder 460)
    - Poetry by Thomas Wistar, M. D., 1837 (Box 121, Folder 461)
    - Poetry by Thomas Wistar, M. D., 1837 (Box 121, Folder 462)
    - Poetry by Thomas Wistar, M. D., n.d. (Box 121, Folder 463)
    - Religious Material: Misc., n.d. (Box 122, Folder 464)
    - Reminiscence by Eunice B. Roberts, 1914 (Box 122, Folder 465)
    - Reminiscence by Margaret C. Cope Kimber, 1933 (Box 122, Folder 466)
    - Report re. art and science in New York City (Box 122, Folder 467)
    - Report by President Pritchett of the Carnegie Foundation re. pensions (Box 122, Folder 468)
    - Reports re. land and buildings, c.1800-05 (Box 122, Folder 469)
    - Sermons: Misc., incl.1845 (Box 122, Folder 470)
    - Testimony of T. Wistar Brown, 1917 (Box 122, Folder 471)
    - Testimony of Richard S. Collins, 1924 (Box 122, Folder 472)
    - Testimony re. Thomas P. Cope, 1954 (Box 122, Folder 473)
    - Testimony re. George Fox, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 474)
    - Testimony re. Martha Haines, 1781 (Box 122, Folder 475)
    - Testimonies re. Mary H. Haines, Theodora Harrison, Alexander Wilson Wistar, 1905-1946 (Box 122, Folder 476)
    - Testimonies re. Arthur Paines Herbert, 1912 (Box 122, Folder 477)
    - Testimonies: Misc., n.d. (Box 122, Folder 478)
    - Testimonies: Poetry, 1813 (Box 122, Folder 479)
    - Testimony re. John Aston Warder, c.1883 (Box 122, Folder 480)
  - Oversized writings
    - Notebook re. "Diseases of Swine", RH III, 1822-31 (Box PB2, Folder 155)
    - RH III Cyphering book, 1800-1801 (Box PB5, Folder 167)
    - RH III Farm Register, 1817-1821 (Box PB5, Folder 168)
    - RH III Barometric Memoranda, 1821-18 (Box PB5, Folder 169)
- Series IV. Financial materials, 1746-1972; 33.25 Linear feet 80 boxes
  The Financial Material includes business and household accounts, bills and receipts, bank books and statements, and tax information which together present a remarkably complete record of the family's financial history. Certain of these materials document the purchase of food, clothing, and many of the furnishings still in the house; the employment of servants; and various improvements made to family properties. Also of interest are the records of family businesses, including two brewhouses (c.1790-1850), a lumber company (1911-1915), and an orchard (c.1940-1963).
  The material in this section is divided into five categories: Accounts, Bills and Receipts, Banking, Miscellaneous Business and Receipt Books. In each category the material is organized by family name and is in chronological order. Oversized material is listed at the end of the category in which it is found.
  - A. Accounts
    - Reuben Haines I
      - 1757-1795 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines I
      - MoT xeroxed, 1794-1801 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - 1794-1798 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Josiah Haines
      - 1789-1793 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Reuben Haines III
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk., 1793-1831 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - 1793-1831 (Box 124, Folder 6)
      - 1801-1803,1809 (Box 124, Folder 6a)
      - 1802-1807 (Box 124, Folder 7)
      - 1805-1806 (Box 124, Folder 8)
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk., 1806-1818 (Box 124, Folder 9)
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk., 1807-1813 (Box 124, Folder 10)
      - 1807-1814 (Box 125, Folder 11)
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk., 1812,1814-1831 (Box 125, Folder 12)
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk. not completed, 1812, 1813 (Box 125, Folder 13)
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk., 1813-1816 (Box 125, Folder 14)
      - MoT xeroxed bound bk., 1814-1817 (Box 125, Folder 15)
      - MoT Xeroxed bound bk, 1814-1825 (Box 126, Folder 16)
      - MoT Xeroxed bound bk, 1814-1825 (Box 126, Folder 17)
      - 1816-1819 (Box 126, Folder 18)
      - 1818-1819 (Box 126, Folder 19)
      - MoT Xeroxed bound bk, 1820-1821 (Box 126, Folder 20)
      - 1820-1823 (Box 126, Folder 21)
      - 1821 (Box 127, Folder 21a)
      - 1821-1823 (Box 127, Folder 22)
      - 1823-1826 (Box 127, Folder 23)
      - 1824-1827 (Box 127, Folder 24)
      - MoT Xeroxed bound bk, 1826-1830 (Box 127, Folder 25)
      - MoT Xeroxed bound bk, 1826-1830 (Box 128, Folder 26)
      - 1827-1831 (Box 128, Folder 27)
      - 1828-1832 (Box 128, Folder 28)
      - 1831 (Box 128, Folder 29)
      - n.d. (Box 128, Folder 30)
      - 1800-1806 (Box 129, Folder 31)
      - 1806-1808 (Box 129, Folder 32)
      - 1807-1808 (Box 129, Folder 33)
      - 1809-1819 (Box 129, Folder 34)
      - 1823-1829 (Box 129, Folder 35)
      - 1830-1839 (Box 129, Folder 36)
      - n.d. (Box 129, Folder 37)
    - Jane Bowne Haines I [also see Box 115, folder 342]
      - 1833-1837 (Box 129, Folder 38)
      - Mot Xeroxed 2 note books, 1840-1842 (Box 129, Folder 39)
      - 1831-1842 (Box 129, Folder 40)
    - Ann Haines
      - 1837-1839 (Box 129, Folder 41)
      - 1809-1811 (Box 129, Folder 42)
    - Sarah Haines
      - 1824 (Box 130, Folder 43)
    - William Henry Bacon
      - bound bk, 1831-1834 (Box 130, Folder 44)
    - Robert Bowne Haines I
      - 1842-1845 (Box 130, Folder 45)
      - bound bk, 1874-1879 (Box 130, Folder 46)
      - 1885-1891 (Box 130, Folder 47)
    - Margaret Vaux Wistar Haines
      - note books, 1891-1895 (Box 130, Folder 48)
      - note books, 1892-1898 (Box 130, Folder 49)
      - incl. taxes papers, 1900-1916, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 50)
    - Jane Reuben Haines
      - 1863-1864 (Box 130, Folder 51)
      - 1865-1907 (Box 130, Folder 52)
      - 1870-1873 (Box 130, Folder 53)
      - 1875-1876 (Box 130, Folder 54)
      - 1876 (Box 130, Folder 55)
      - 1878-1880 (Box 131, Folder 55a)
      - 1880-1887 (Box 131, Folder 55b)
      - 1883-1892 (Box 131, Folder 55c)
      - 1888-1894 (Box 131, Folder 55)
      - 1894-1900 (Box 131, Folder 55e)
      - 1895-1897 (Box 131, Folder 55)
      - 1898-1902 (Box 131, Folder 55g)
      - 1901-1905 (Box 131, Folder 55h)
      - 1905 (Box 131, Folder 55i)
      - 1906-1911 (Box 132, Folder 55j)
      - 1889-1891 (Box 132, Folder 55k)
      - 1892-1894 (Box 132, Folder 55l)
      - 1895-1897 (Box 132, Folder 55m)
      - 1898-1903 (Box 132, Folder 55n)
      - 1904-1911 (Box 133, Folder 55o)
      - n.d. (Box 133, Folder 55p)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines II
      - 1872 (Box 132, Folder 55q)
      - 1874-1880 (Box 132, Folder 55r)
      - 1876 (Box 132, Folder 55s)
      - 1888-1889 (Box 133, Folder 56)
      - 1890, 1891 (Box 133, Folder 57)
      - 1892-1896 (Box 133, Folder 58)
      - 1897-1905 (Box 133, Folder 59)
      - 1906-1909 (Box 133, Folder 60)
      - 1909-1922 (Box 133, Folder 61)
      - 1910-1912 (Box 134, Folder 62)
      - 1913-1916 (Box 134, Folder 63)
      - 1917-1920 (Box 134, Folder 64)
      - 1917-1936 (Box 134, Folder 65)
      - 1921-1925 (Box 134, Folder 66)
      - 1927 (Box 135, Folder 67)
      - 1919-1927 (Box 135, Folder 68)
      - 1920-1935 (Box 135, Folder 69)
      - 1922-1928 (Box 135, Folder 70)
      - 1926-1934 (Box 135, Folder 71)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 136, Folder 72)
      - 1877-1884 (Box 136, Folder 73)
      - 1887-1896 (Box 136, Folder 74)
      - 1897-1899 (Box 136, Folder 75)
      - 1900-1906 (Box 136, Folder 76)
      - 1907-1909 (Box 136, Folder 77)
      - 1910-1912 (Box 136, Folder 78)
      - 1913-1915 (Box 136, Folder 79)
      - 1916-1920 (Box 136, Folder 80)
      - 1921-1922 (Box 136, Folder 81)
      - 1924-1926 (Box 136, Folder 82)
      - 1926-1929 (Box 136, Folder 83)
      - 1929-1934 (Box 136, Folder 84)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 137, Folder 85)
      - 1930-1926 (Box 137, Folder 86)
      - 1932 (Box 137, Folder 87)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 137, Folder 88)
      - n.d. (Box 137, Folder 89)
      - n.d. (Box 137, Folder 90)
    - Robert Bowne Haines II
      - 1878-1898 (Box 137, Folder 91)
      - 1880 (Box 137, Folder 92)
      - 1885-1888 (Box 137, Folder 93)
      - 1891-1895 (Box 137, Folder 94)
      - 1896-1899 (Box 138, Folder 95)
      - 1899 (Box 138, Folder 96)
      - 1900-1920 (Box 138, Folder 97)
      - 1920-1925 (Box 138, Folder 98)
      - 1926-1928 (Box 138, Folder 99)
      - 1929-1931 (Box 138, Folder 100)
      - n.d. (Box 138, Folder 101)
    - Mary Morton Haines
      - 1921 (Box 138, Folder 102)
      - 1925-1934 (Box 138, Folder 103)
    - William Jones Haines
      - 1888 (Box 139, Folder 104)
      - 1902-1913 (Box 139, Folder 105)
      - 1914-1917 (Box 139, Folder 106)
      - 1915-1916 (Box 139, Folder 107)
      - 1915-1920 (Box 139, Folder 108)
      - 1916 (Box 139, Folder 109)
      - 1916-1917 (Box 139, Folder 110)
      - 1917 (Box 139, Folder 111)
    - Jane Bowne Haines II
      - 1884-1901 (Box 140, Folder 112)
      - 1910-1912 (Box 140, Folder 113)
      - 1922-1937 (Box 140, Folder 114)
      - 1937 (Box 140, Folder 115)
    - Robert Bowne Haines III
      - 1922 (Box 140, Folder 116)
      - 1923 (Box 140, Folder 117)
      - 1924 (Box 140, Folder 118)
      - 1924, 1933 (Box 140, Folder 119)
      - 1925 (Box 140, Folder 120)
      - 1926 (Box 140, Folder 121)
      - 1928 (Box 140, Folder 122)
      - 1929 (Box 140, Folder 123)
      - 1930 (Box 140, Folder 124)
      - 1932 (Box 140, Folder 125)
      - 1933 (Box 140, Folder 126)
      - 1934 (Box 140, Folder 127)
      - 1934 (Box 140, Folder 128)
      - 1935 (Box 140, Folder 129)
      - 1935,1936 (Box 140, Folder 130)
      - 1935-1937 (Box 141, Folder 131)
      - 1936 (Box 141, Folder 132)
      - 1936-1938 (Box 141, Folder 133)
      - 1937 (Box 141, Folder 134)
      - 1937 (Box 141, Folder 135)
      - 1937 (Box 141, Folder 136)
      - 1938 (Box 141, Folder 137)
      - 1938-1941 (Box 141, Folder 138)
      - 1939 (Box 141, Folder 139)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 141, Folder 140)
      - 1940 (Box 141, Folder 141)
      - 1940,1941 (Box 141, Folder 142)
      - 1941 (Box 142, Folder 143)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 142, Folder 144)
      - 1942 (Box 142, Folder 145)
      - 1942 (Box 142, Folder 146)
      - 1943 (Box 142, Folder 147)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 142, Folder 148)
      - 1944 (Box 142, Folder 149)
      - 1944 (Box 142, Folder 150)
      - 1944 (Box 142, Folder 151)
      - 1945 (Box 142, Folder 152)
      - 1945 (Box 142, Folder 153)
      - 1945-1946 (Box 142, Folder 154)
      - 1946 (Box 143, Folder 155)
      - 1946 (Box 143, Folder 156)
      - 1946 (Box 143, Folder 157)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 143, Folder 158)
      - 1947 (Box 143, Folder 159)
      - 1948 (Box 143, Folder 160)
      - 1948 (Box 143, Folder 161)
      - 1949 (Box 143, Folder 162)
      - 1950 (Box 143, Folder 163)
      - 1951 (Box 143, Folder 164)
      - 1952 (Box 143, Folder 165)
      - 1953 (Box 143, Folder 166)
      - 1954 (Box 143, Folder 167)
      - 1955-56 (Box 143, Folder 168)
      - 1957-59 (Box 143, Folder 169)
      - 1958 (Box 143, Folder 170)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 143, Folder 171)
      - 1962 (Box 143, Folder 172)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 143, Folder 173)
      - n.d. (Box 143, Folder 174)
      - n.d. (Box 143, Folder 175)
    - Mary Troth Haines
      - 1947-1953 (Box 144, Folder 176)
    - Murray Cheston Haines
      - 1942 (Box 144, Folder 177)
    - Caspar Wistar, M.D.
      - 1782-1795 (Box 144, Folder 178)
    - A. M. Garrigues
      - 1803 (Box 144, Folder 179)
    - Laura S. Voorhees
      - 1930 (Box 144, Folder 180)
    - Miscellaneous Accounts
      - n.d. (Box 144, Folder 181)
      - n.d. (Box 144, Folder 182)
    - OVERSIZED accounts
      - Account Books
        - Haines, Caspar Wistar I Account Book incl. also RH III memoranda 1827-1829, 1785-1797 (Box OS1, Folder 1)
        - Haines, Caspar Wistar I "Day Book" Germantown Brewhouse, 1794-1797 (Box OS1, Folder 2)
        - Haines, Reuben III Account Book, 1813 (Box OS1, Folder 3)
        - Haines, Reuben III Account Book incl. also CWH I 1797-1801, 1823-1824 (Box OS1, Folder 4)
        - Day book, dry goods store (?), 1797-1802 (Box OS22, Folder 151A)
        - Haines, Robert Bowne I Account Book, 1848-1861 (Box PB6, Folder 170)
        - Haines, Robert Bowne I Account Book "Bonds & Mortgages", 1848-1870 (Box PB6, Folder 171)
        - Haines, Robert Bowne I Account Book, 1850-1855 (Box PB6, Folder 172)
        - Haines, Robert Bowne I Account Book "Heidelberg Farm Accounts", 1850-1870 (Box PB6, Folder 173)
        - Haines, Robert Bowne I Account Book "Cheltenham Nurseries Sales", 1859-1865 (Box PB6, Folder 174)
        - Haines, Robert Bowne I Account Book "Day Book", 1858-1871 (Box PB6, Folder 175)